What if you had a second chance with the one that got away?
Before Sunset is a drama, romance film directed by Richard Linklater.
Nine years later, Jesse travels across Europe giving readings from a book
he wrote about the night he spent in Vienna with Celine.
After his reading in Paris, Celine finds him, and they spend part of the
day together before Jesse has to again leave for a flight.
They are both in relationships now, and Jesse has a son, but as their strong
feelings for each other start to return, both confess a longing for more.
Jesse, played by Ethan Hawke.
Céline, played by Julie Delpy.
Bookstore Manager, played by Vernon Dobtcheff.
Journalist #1, played by Louise Lemoine Torrès.
Journalist #2, played by Rodolphe Pauly.
Waitress, played by Mariane Plasteig.
Before Sunset is a 2004 American romantic drama film directed by Richard Linklater, who co-wrote the
screenplay with Ethan Hawke and Julie Delpy, from a story by Linklater and Kim Krizan.
It is the first film by Warner Independent Pictures.
The sequel to Before Sunrise (1995) and the second installment in the Before trilogy, Before Sunset
follows Jesse (Hawke) and Céline (Delpy) as they reunite nine years later in Paris.
Linklater, Krizan, Hawke, and Delpy began developing a larger budget sequel in
the 1990s, but failed to secure funding to begin production.
After writing the film independently, with portions inspired by Hawke's separation (and eventual divorce) from Uma Thurman, the writers came together in 2003 and
incorporated elements of their individual screenplays, as well as other scenes written during development of Before Sunrise, to create the final screenplay.
Principal photography took place entirely in Paris, and the
film is considered to take place in real time.
Delpy also contributed original music to the film's soundtrack.
Before Sunset premiered at the Berlin International Film Festival on February 10,
2004; it was theatrically released in the United States on July 2, 2004.
It grossed $15 million worldwide and received widespread critical acclaim, particularly for
Linklater's direction, the performances and chemistry of its leads, and its screenplay.
It received numerous accolades, being nominated for the Academy Award for Best Adapted Screenplay, and appeared on many
publications' lists of the best films of the year, with some calling it one of the best of the decade.
It was followed by a third film, Before Midnight, in 2013.
The film explores themes of journalist, talking,
soulmates, walking, paris, france.
The tone is emotional.